# **GAGAN SHETTY**

Reading, UK **↑** +44 7824061008 **\** 

Portfolio Website - https://gagan-shetty.github.io/Portfolio/

# **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

I am an experienced data professional. My experience involves working in extensive data wrangling and extraction from various sources, analyzing data with multiple relevant statistical techniques to extract trends and insights, developing machine learning models for developing predictive insights from the data and reporting the data with advanced bi tools and graphing techniques. I also like to explore and apply advancements in technology related to data such as usage of GenAI to develop applications. I can create effective storytelling backed with statistics to ensure communication of ideas to stakeholders from any background and understanding. I am well versed in applying my skillset in any job context where using power of data has previously not yet been attempted.

## **EDUCATION**

MSc | Aston University (Post Graduation) - (Sept 2021 to Sept 2022)

Course: MSc Business Analytics. Grade: Merit. Individual top scorer in multiple analytics study modules.

B. E | PES institute of technology (Graduation) - (Aug 2014 to May 2018) - 8.5 CGPA

## **SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS**

<u>Data Analytics –</u> Highly experienced in Data Analytics and able to work with multiple software's and programming languages. Key strengths include turning raw data into actionable insights with effective storytelling and visualizations. Proficient in applying advanced methods to extract Descriptive, Prescriptive and Predictive insights about a program or a product.

<u>Machine learning</u> Well versed in key concepts of machine learning such as – Data wrangling, Feature Engineering, Model training, Model deployment. Knowledge of all key ML algorithms and working mechanism of hyperparameters.

Extensive research on feature engineering as part of master's thesis and applied knowledge of prominent algorithms.

<u>GenAl –</u> Working with latest models to create bespoke applications for text analytics. Scope of work mainly included working with cloud based foundational models (Mainly GCP Palm2 – Text Bison model LLM), training and fine tuning the LLM models.

<u>Python</u> Highly proficient in development of tools in python including OOP. Mainly used for Data applications such as data extraction, data wrangling and other data operations some more work include Automation script development for efficiency improvement, Data Synchronization solution development between project management software's – **Jira** and **Azure DevOps** (Ref portfolio for details) **REST API, OData** – Solutions were implemented which involved data extraction, data updating using these protocols.

<u>Power BI Development – Proficient in Data Transformation and Data Connections using Python Scripts/ OData query/Azure Boards etc. and highly effective Data Visualization</u>

<u>Cloud –</u> Google Cloud (Professional Machine Learning Engineer – Certification in progress)

**AWS** (Cloud Practitioner Certified)

<u>CMI</u> – Level 7 Award – Strategic Management and Leadership Practice awarded by chartered management institute.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Deloitte - Consulting, London, UK (September 2022 - Current) 1 year

**PMO Data Analyst** – Worked in Technical PMO team as a Data Analyst for a Financial Services client undergoing wealth platform transformation. Day to day involved.

- Extensive data aggregation and analysis to ensure on track delivery of the program.
- Lead for implementing PowerBI dashboards from excel dashboard in the project for displaying live and interactive view, this reduced lead time of report creation by around 80% and provided control to management to filter and see required info.
- Identifying and formulating key metrics and circulating it to upper-level management for tracking progress and status
- Python solutions development to aggregate and analyze data, due to the widely dispersed nature of the data.
- Developed automation scripts to automatically build report and circulate it to intended audience.

Other notable works in Deloitte

- Led Test PMO Reporting capability where standardized and advanced tools were developed stored and segregated for use as accelerators in client bids.
- GenAl Key member in attempts for early adoption of GenAl, work included scoping use cases and applications for usage of GenAl in day-to-day applications for the op unit and create bespoke tools out of it for analyzing software requirements, acceptance criteria's, generating test cases etc.

## Otis Elevators (July 2018 - July 2021) 3 years

**Data Consultant, Global Technical Data Team** – Founding member of Global Technical Data Team. Responsibilities included extensive analysis of data using excel and using the insights to develop and deploy solutions. Key achievements include.

- Analyzed massive datasets which stored design data in excel from multiple engineering centers and efficiently designed data architecture and hierarchy to reduce lead time in common design implementations by around 50%
- Deployed multiple data tools across different region to optimize efficiency of design transfers.
- Liaised with multiple stakeholders across different countries and operations to identify constraints and devise optimum solution.
- Created business process automations with the aid of python, power automate to drastically reduce manual efforts in simple process management.

# PORTFOLIO (Link to my website - https://gagan-shetty.github.io/Portfolio/)

## 1. Research and published articles

- Exploratory Data Analysis Part 1 (published in medium)
  - Topics covered Data inspection and wrangling to handle and fix different issues with data. Univariate
    analysis for various variable types with visualization and statistic summarization techniques
- Exploratory Data Analysis Part 2 (published in medium)
  - Topics covered Multivariate analysis for different combinations of variables with visualization and statistic summarization techniques. Hypothesis testing techniques to confirm intuitions statistically.

## 2. Data Projects

Dataset was used to demonstrate capabilities in advances analytics relating to

- Descriptive analytics with multiple linear progression Housing dataset, price prediction
- Clustering— Customer segmentation for banking
- Conjoint analysis Market feedback research
- Time series forecasting with decomposition Airline customer prediction.
- Artificial neural network Stock price prediction

### 3. Machine learning & GenAl

- Al / ML Hackathon, 1<sup>st</sup> Place out of 54 participants.
- Feature Engineering and Feature Selection Comprehensive Analysis with Machine Learning Simulation [Research Thesis]
- GenAl powered tool for Software Requirement Artifact Analysis

#### 4. Coding and Automation

- Data Synchronization Tool Jira and Azure DevOps A tool built on python framework to automatically synchronize work items between Jira and Azure DevOps. Packages mainly REST API, Azure Pipelines were used with GitHub for codebase management.
- Automation script for report generation and auto email Reduced lead time and increased efficiency of report generation and circulation greatly by creating python backed scripts with pandas for data wrangling operations and other packages such as Microsoft COM for mail automation.

More information regarding the above, link to codebase if available can be found in my portfolio website. - <a href="https://gagan-shetty.github.io/Portfolio/">https://gagan-shetty.github.io/Portfolio/</a>